{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Animal viruses with capsids displaying helical symmetry include", "opta": "measles and mumps", "optb": "influenza", "optc": "rabies", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Icosahedral viruses are generally", "opta": "polio viruses", "optb": "adeno viruses", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Negative strand ssRNA viruses need to have a preformed replicase when they invade a mammalian cell because they", "opta": "use it to terminate transcripts when they copy host cell mRNA", "optb": "have to make a positive strand copy that can be translated", "optc": "use it to modify host enzymes that are recruited for viral replication", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following reflects the correct order of events that take place during the multiplication of a virus?", "opta": "Attachment, penetration, maturation, biosynthesis, release", "optb": "Penetration, attachment, biosynthesis, maturation, release", "optc": "Attachment, penetration, biosynthesis, maturation, release", "optd": "Attachment, release, biosynthesis, maturation, penetration", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What can be coated to the plastic dish if an ELISA is performed to directly detect polio virus?", "opta": "Patient serum", "optb": "Anti-polio antibody", "optc": "Polio capsid protein", "optd": "Colored substrate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Influenza virus undergoes antigenic shift resulting in major antigenic changes by which of the following mechanisms?", "opta": "Somatic recombination of heavy and light chains", "optb": "Expression of several different capsule types", "optc": "Changing the receptor binding canyon that docks with the host receptor", "optd": "Reassortment of RNA segments from different influenza viruses", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nucleocapsid is covered by an outer membrane like structure called", "opta": "envelope", "optb": "covering", "optc": "membronocapsid", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of interferon is produced by virus-infected cells?", "opta": "\u03b1", "optb": "\u03b2", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fluorescence microscopy can be used for the diagnosis of", "opta": "Subacute sclerosing panencephalitis", "optb": "Herpes simplex encephalitis", "optc": "Rabies", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Viral matrix proteins are", "opta": "exposed on the surface of the virus", "optb": "found mainly on naked viruses", "optc": "anchor the envelope of enveloped viruses", "optd": "part of the nucleoprotein core of viruses", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mumps vaccine is prepared from the cultures of", "opta": "chick fibroblasts", "optb": "African green monkey cells", "optc": "healthy calves", "optd": "sheep", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The microbes which are most likely to be completely dependent on a plant or animal host are", "opta": "viruses", "optb": "bacteria", "optc": "fungi", "optd": "algae", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The two major components of viruses are", "opta": "fat and protein", "optb": "nucleic acid and protein", "optc": "carbohydrate and nucleic acid", "optd": "fat and carbohydrate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transcription of the viral nucleic acid into mRNA is not necessary in case of", "opta": "RNA viruses", "optb": "ds DNA viruses", "optc": "ss DNA viruses", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "West Nile virus can cause a disease in human beings that may be transmitted from an infected bird to a person by a mosquito. This is an example of", "opta": "endogenous infection", "optb": "fomite borne disease", "optc": "arthropod borne disease", "optd": "nosocomial infection", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the positive strand in double stranded RNA viruses stands for?", "opta": "rRNA", "optb": "tRNA", "optc": "mRNA", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following characteristics would not be used to classify viruses?", "opta": "Type of cell wall structure", "optb": "Type of nucleic acid", "optc": "Presence of an envelope", "optd": "Symmetry", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Interanuclear inclusion bodies are found in cells infected with", "opta": "Parvoviruses", "optb": "Herpesviruses", "optc": "Adenoviruses", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reovirus and influenza virus contain", "opta": "10 different segments of dsRNA and 8 different segments of ssRNA respectively", "optb": "8 different segments of dsRNA and 10 different segments of ssRNA respectively", "optc": "5 different segments of dsRNA and 7 different segments of ssRNA respectively", "optd": "7 different segments of dsRNA and 5different segments of ssRNA respectively", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of interferon is produced by T lymphocytes?", "opta": "\u03b1", "optb": "\u03b2", "optc": "\u03b3", "optd": "\u03b3 and \u03b2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transfer of infection from cell to cell occurs mainly by direct transfer of virions via", "opta": "plasmodesmata", "optb": "cytodesmata", "optc": "protodesmata", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Intracytoplasmic inclusion bodies are found in cells infected with", "opta": "Rabies virus", "optb": "Vaccinia virus", "optc": "Fowlpox virus", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the function of positive strand in double stranded RNA viruses?", "opta": "Synthesis of protein", "optb": "Production of ribosomes", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following virus is transmitted by the respiratory route?", "opta": "Rhinovirus", "optb": "Coronavirus", "optc": "Measles virus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The predominant lipid substance found in the viral envelope is", "opta": "phospholipids", "optb": "glycolipids", "optc": "neutral fat", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Supercoiling refers to the extra turns in the structure of ds DNA due to the action of", "opta": "DNA gyrase", "optb": "DNA pyrase", "optc": "RNA gyrase", "optd": "RNA pyrase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tissue structure deteriorates as the virus multiplies. This deterioration is called", "opta": "aneuploidy", "optb": "protopathic effect", "optc": "cytopathic effect", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The structural abnormality of cells is termed as", "opta": "hyperplasia", "optb": "anaplasia", "optc": "metastasis", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The penetration of animal viruses into attached cells occur by mechanisms consisting of engulfment of whole virions by the cells in a phagocytic process called", "opta": "vitropexis", "optb": "viropexis", "optc": "ectodesmata", "optd": "vivopexis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Viropexis takes place in the phagocytic vacuoles and is due to the action of enzymes", "opta": "DNA gyrase", "optb": "lysosomal protease", "optc": "lysosomal lipase", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Negri bodies are found in cells infected with", "opta": "Paramyxoviruses", "optb": "Vaccinia virus", "optc": "Fowlpox virus", "optd": "Rabies virus", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The uncontrolled proliferation of cells is termed as", "opta": "hyperplasia", "optb": "anaplasia", "optc": "metastasis", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following virus is transmitted by genital route?", "opta": "Papillomaviruses", "optb": "Herpes simplex virus type 2", "optc": "Hepatitis B virus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The RNA sarcoma viruses, the most strongly transforming viruses may transform which of the following cells in a culture?", "opta": "fibroblasts", "optb": "myoblasts", "optc": "iris epithelial", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plant viruses penetrate host cells through transient ores called", "opta": "ectodesmata", "optb": "endodesmata", "optc": "cytodesmata", "optd": "protodesmata", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}